[A Moment But Forever]
[Episode 20]
When Yuanzhong was transferring power to Lu Chen,
the Demon Dragon thought
Yuanzhong would be a better
vessel for possession.
So it transformed into a demonic energy
and entered Yuanzhong's
sea of consciousness.
I fought against him for days
but was ultimately defeated.
He severely wounded me
and entered the cave.
The Demon Dragon entered
Yuanzhong's Cave of Spiritual Consciousness?
Correct.
This cave
is Yuanzhong's realm of consciousness.
It has nine levels in total,
intertwined and reflecting each other,
all of which are crucial.
For each level that's eroded,
it's as if Yuanzhong
has died a little.
If he enters
the deepest ninth level,
his spiritual consciousness will be erased,
and this body will be possessed by the Demon Dragon.
What should we do then?
I'm severely wounded
and can only rely on external help.
Since you're an external consciousness,
you can help me drive out the Demon Dragon.
I understand.
So, which level
has the Demon Dragon reached now?
Based on the time elapsed,
it must be approaching the ninth level.
What are we waiting for then?
Let's hurry!
Once upon a time, Zhuangzi dreamed he was a butterfly,
a very lifelike butterfly.
He was so happy!
He didn't know he was Zhuangzi.
This is the first level.
It seems to be the Youhu Clan's school
before the great battle.
A butterfly indeed.
Tanghua,
stand up!
You little brat!
Who let you wear boots?
Why is he hitting him for wearing boots?
Isn't everyone wearing boots here?
This is a dream.
It's formed by thoughts, without rules or limits.
It's completely different from reality,
strange and bizarre.
Naturally, anything is possible.
Alright.
So how do we
get to the next level?
The consciousness owner of each level is the entrance.
So we just need to find
the Yuanzhong of this level.
Which one is he?
All the people here
are created by his thoughts.
So from my perspective,
they're all him.
I can't distinguish them.
You can't recognize him?
Correct.
That's why I need you.
Which one do you think is him?
Which one could be him?
Quick, look at me.
Look!
I can fly now!
I can fly now.
It's truly lawless and boundless.
It seems it's really him.
I can fly now.
You can fly too?
This bird is really beautiful.
We still need to rely on mechanical birds.
We're not as skilled as you.
You don't need to rely on anything.
The sky is vast and the earth is wide.
You can go anywhere.
You can run and fly
whenever you want.
Come, reach out your hand.
This is so much fun.
Is this the former Liujiao Palace?
It's the most recent one.
Dreams are disordered.
There's no need to follow the rules of time either.
I see.
Is that all you've got?
With your level of skill,
even if you practice for another 500 years,
you still won't be a match for me.
That voice sounds so familiar.
You useless people,
get out of my sight!
Yes.
It's not just the voice that's familiar.
Isn't this you?
So in his heart,
this is how I am.
Here comes another newcomer.
Kneel before me now!
Pay your respects to me, the first handmaiden.
First... handmaiden?
You won't kneel, huh?
Then pay with your life!
Where on earth is the consciousness owner of this level?
How would I know?
You have to find him yourself.
I don't have time to search!
I understand now.
What?
Although she's overbearing,
she's always tightly
guarding this gate.
You think that what she's protecting...
Should be the consciousness owner of this level.
Don't go in!
Is it him?
Stop it, all of you!
Don't touch him!
I forbid you to touch him!
She's clearly protecting him,
yet she can't get close to him,
and she looks like this too.
It seems in his heart,
he both trusts and doubts you.
He wants to rely on you
but also wants to stay away from you.
He also feels that you're dangerous.
Don't touch him!
Are you ready?
-Elder!
I beg the Elder to show mercy.
Please spare my son.
Elders, I beg you all.
Elder, Elder,
I beg you to spare my son.
He's my only son.
Elder, I beg you.
Please let him go, Elder.
-Father!
-Husband!
You're out of touch with the times.
Husband!
Spare no one.
Father.
Kill.
It wasn't like this.
I've heard about this incident.
There were indeed many children
who were taken to Tianqu Peak.
Their families came to negotiate
and the two sides clashed.
That's how the disaster unfolded.
But at that time, Dingxu and Xinyao
weren't even at the scene.
This is his dream.
He wasn't there at the time.
All of this
must be his imagination.
Elders, Elders,
I beg for your mercy.
Please spare my son.
It's starting again.
How could this happen?
This dream is endless,
without beginning or end.
It's clear that this matter
holds a significant place in his heart.
Elder, have mercy.
Please spare my son.
Elder, please release my son.
Elders, I beg you all,
please spare my son.
Elders…
You're out of touch with the times.
It seems Yuanzhong isn't in this scene.
This dream is so
painful for him.
He certainly wouldn't want
to be present himself.
But he must be in here somewhere,
right?
Yes.
Where do you think he might be?
His parents and sister
died because of him.
He feels deeply guilty,
yet is powerless to change anything.
I guess he should be
the most helpless one.
Found him.
Let's quickly move to the next level.
Wait a moment.
It's okay now. It's okay now.
There, there, there. It's okay now.
There, there.
We can go now.
They told me to guard them,
but with my limited magical power,
I can't handle this.
Yunniang?
My good Kai Shan,
you've come at the right time.
Quick, save them.
I'll take care of this.
Alright.
Yuanzhong.
A woman?
This isn't right.
I'm the only one locked up here.
Looks like I'm dreaming again.
No, you're not dreaming.
Yuanzhong,
look at me.
I'm Ji Tanyin.
Don't you recognize me?
This dream is a bit noisy.
What are you trying to do?
I just want to touch you.
Don't try that.
You're trying to take my golden hoop, aren't you?
I'm not.
Of course you won't admit it.
I'm warning you,
don't be delusional.
This golden hoop is very important to me.
Thanks to it
suppressing my Divine Hand,
I'm able to understand
many things I couldn't before.
Let me tell you a secret.
I've actually had an epiphany.
I've seen through it all.
I completely understand now.
Understand what?
Everything they said is true.
The Five Sins really exist.
Take Dingxu for example.
You're a person in my dream,
so you must know about Dingxu, right?
Then tell me,
why did Dingxu
instigate everyone
to lock me up?
Why?
Because he's jealous.
He's jealous that I became
the host of the Divine Hand.
He's jealous of the
glorious military achievements I've made.
He covets this power,
but he can't obtain it.
So he suppresses me,
wishing he could lock me in hell
for eternity with no chance of redemption.
That seems to make some sense.
Of course it makes sense,
because this is the truth.
Think about it again.
Tanghua…
Why did Tanghua hide the truth
and stand with Dingxu?
Why?
Because he's a hypocrite.
He has never
treated me as a true friend.
Everything he said was false,
all just to appease
and deceive me.
He wants
to gain benefits,
yet he also wants to be seen as a good person.
See how hypocritical he is?
And this is just what's shown to me.
But if you look at the mortal realm,
the affairs of the world are no different.
The War Demon Clan
abandoned war for the sake of survival.
But in this vast world,
how could there not be room
for a clan?
They were just too greedy
and obsessed.
They wanted too much.
With the same principle,
let's look at the bigger picture.
This war between gods and demons
was nothing but a seed of cruelty
that had been infinitely magnified.
Think about it carefully.
What's the essential difference
between gods and demons?
They're just manifestations of human desires.
One thought makes one a god.
One thought makes one a demon.
It's not like that.
No?
Don't tell me you believe in gods.
I do.
Ignorance.
Utter ignorance.
The believers chant prayers day and night,
bowing three times and kowtowing nine times daily.
They rejoice when gods love the world
and grieve when gods abandon it.
But in essence,
isn't it just worshipping divine power
and the powerful,
while also fearing
being abandoned by the powerful?
If this isn't ignorance, then what is it?
The ignorance of the weak
is incurable.
Therefore,
they are not wrong.
The Five Sins are the source of all evil.
To restore clarity to this world,
we must cleanse the Five Sins.
If the Five Sins are not eliminated,
the Great Way will be blocked.
If the Great Way is blocked,
then the small evils of the world
will accumulate
and become great evils, extreme evils.
Then this world will be done for.
Do you think I'm right?
Let's eat something first.
I'm not hungry.
You should eat even if you're not hungry.
It's a good time to think about what you said.
You think I'm noisy.
I don't.
If you don't, then think about it now.
I can think without eating.
What I want to say is simple.
The Five Sins truly exist.
The Five Sins are the source of all evil.
To restore clarity to this world,
we must cleanse these Five Sins.
The Five Sins are extraordinary.
They're interdependent and mutually reinforcing.
Take jealousy for example.
Without jealousy, there would be no greed.
Without greed, there would be no hypocrisy.
-Without hypocrisy, there would be no...
-Yuanzhong!
You're too tired, Yuanzhong.
Take a rest.
I can't. I can't.
It's okay.
Everything you said is right.
This is just a dream.
Come out quickly!
Come on!
Come, come here, quickly!
You go first.
[War Demon Clan, Han Jiang]
Yunniang!
Yunniang, Yunniang.
Yunniang, how are you?
Don't scare me.
Jiu.
Take the children and go first.
What are you saying?
I can't escape anymore.
I'm just a burden if you take me with you.
Don't say that.
Yunniang.
♫Time never defeats the fleeting world♫
Do you remember
♫Stars turn, shining upon the passing traveler♫
the notebook I gave you?
Of course I remember.
♫The wind rises, flowers fall and bloom again♫
♫Awaiting what’s lost to be regained♫
Give it back to me.
♫These countless sorrows and joys♫
Let me see it.
♫Dusk and dawn, only you make parting hard♫
You must let me see it.
Understand?
♫I'm willing to risk my life for this♫
What are you going to do?
Silly.
♫If our promise♫
♫Is to share this land and rivers♫
I'm going to save you.
♫If fate leads us astray♫
♫Life and death become our bond♫
♫Storms heal with time♫
♫Memories will shine in the end♫
I forgot to tell you.
You look so beautiful in your
♫That very first heartbeat, I will remember until the last♫
wedding dress today.
Jiu.
Jiu, Jiu.
A bunch of unknown
bastards who came out of nowhere.
Come on!
Get a taste of my
ultimate moves!
Lu Chen.
Kill the enemy first.
I didn't expect
the sea of consciousness to really be a sea.
Why didn't you appear just now?
The Yuanzhong from that previous layer
was unstable.
He was in a state of frenzy.
If he saw me,
he might've done
unpredictable things.
Anyway, we don't have much time left.
Which layer of the dream is this?
In this sea of consciousness, there's nothing
other than the water.
Where could he be?
Could he be in the water?
No.
Are you sure?
Definitely.
You're so certain
because your true self
has already searched in the water.
Stop pretending.
You're not the original consciousness at all.
I underestimated you.
Ji Tanyin!
Whatever you're doing,
you need to come out quickly!
I can't hold on much longer.
How dare you, mortal!
In the presence of your lord,
kneel before me at once!
You're not worthy of my respect.
How dare you use me to traverse the dreams?
You demon, you've got some nerve.
How did you figure it out?
Because it doesn't make sense.
If you were truly Yuanzhong's original self,
why couldn't you recognize
the consciousness owner of each layer?
I finally figured it out.
You are
instinctively rejected by Yuanzhong.
That's why he doesn't reveal himself to you.
So there's only one possibility left.
So that's how it is.
Too bad you've only realized it now.
It's too late.
We're already in his sea of consciousness.
Now I just need to find a way
to sink all the way down,
bypassing the other layers of dreams
straight to the ninth layer.
This is where your journey ends!
Die!
Come and try if you dare,
little girl.
As a mortal,
you might be quite powerful,
but to challenge me,
you're still far too weak.
If it weren't for the years of dormancy
that greatly reduced my power,
you'd be dead by now.
Such confidence.
Yuanzhong.
Original consciousness owner?
Is he alone?
Yes.
He's the Demon Lord's mount.
After the war between gods and demons,
he was hidden at the bottom of Orange Lake.
Through Pei Jiu,
he entered your body,
attempting to take over your body.
I've encountered many people on my way here.
Fighting them
took some time.
What you've seen might all have been him.
Things can change, but the essence remains the same.
It's just child's play.
Yuanzhong,
you've been deceived by the Five Sins.
Don't be so stubborn.
Yuanzhong.
This is all your fault.
Your cruelty knows no bounds.
Your hands are already stained with blood.
Atone for your sins.
Look at these people.
Which one do you like?
That's right.
I know which one you like.
Yuanzhong, don't resist.
Atone for your sins.
Your life has no meaning.
Come to me quickly.
If you were performing on the street,
I might be interested
in giving you a few coins.
What's wrong? Don't you like this?
Isn't this how she looked
in your imaginations?
Look at that sea.
It's pitch black with raging storms and snow.
Your sea of consciousness is so dark.
It's almost identical to the mindset
of us demons.
You were born a demon seed.
Quickly join us.
Become one with me.
Become a member of the demon clan.
If you don't take the easy way, you'll have to take the hard way.
I'll kill you two.
Leave this to me.
I'll go with you.
♫Ask the heavens♫
♫I don't know why I'm without a home♫
♫I'm at a dead end♫
♫And I have to surrender and accept my destiny♫
Ji Tanyin, why did you come out?
♫I'm the wandering one♫
How's Yuanzhong?
♫My body and mind, falling into dust♫
♫Only the moon in the sky♫
♫Shines upon the lifelong decay♫
♫The scars you can't see♫
♫Are the proof of my struggle♫
♫Be your own last straw of hope♫
♫Why do you have to go alone?♫
♫Let me learn to be fearless♫
♫I live with no regrets♫
♫Who deserves to be crushed?♫
♫Don't tell me what's right or wrong♫
♫I rebel against fate♫
♫I'm willing to risk my life♫
♫No matter how dangerous it is♫
♫I will travel the world and scatter the fog♫
Today, I wish to cleanse the Five Sins with heavenly fire.
The five of you are needed as sacrifices.
Are you willing to sacrifice yourselves?
We are willing.
Very well.
To keep the heavenly fire burning,
the Divine Hand must also serve as fuel.
As the saying goes,
if I don't enter hell, who will?
You actually want to use the Divine Left Hand
to destroy this world?
I won't destroy this world.
I'll merely cleanse it with heavenly fire.
You've become a demon.
Become a demon?
I heard you want to devour me.
Oh no, I can't hold it back anymore.
Hold on.
Yuanzhong hasn't woken up yet.
Do you think I don't want to hold on?
Yuanzhong.
You're alright now?
I was fine all along.
I originally wanted to let you
live a bit longer,
but you're seeking your own death.
So don't blame me.
Come in.
You're awake.
Is everything alright?
It feels like I've had a long dream,
but I can't remember
what happened in the dream.
The matters here are settled.
Are you willing
to continue to Yandu with me?
Of course.
Really?
Yuanzhong,
my life, death, honor, and disgrace are all tied to you.
I will naturally put you first in everything.
Besides, we made
that decision together.
Then let's pack up
and set off immediately.
Alright.
Yunniang, you're here.
Miss Ji,
I'm here to see Pei Jiu.
Is he inside?
He…
I'm here. What's the matter?
I'm wearing a hairpin today.
It was given by you.
It was given by Pei Jiu.
Why are you in such a hurry
to distance yourself from me?
We were just passing acquaintances.
There was never any relationship.
I won't interfere with Pei Jiu's life,
and as for my life,
I hope he can do the same.
Just passing acquaintances?
You've really changed into a different person.
You left
this with me.
You were worried you might forget,
so you specifically instructed me
to make sure I handed it to you personally.
In Pei Jiu's notebook,
there are many records
of his past with Yunniang.
After Lu Chen reads it,
he'll be swayed, right?
It's only human nature.
But what if
he decides not to go with you?
He won't read it.
My name is Lu Chen.
I'm one of the weapon spirits
of the Youhu Clan's High Priest.
Due to certain circumstances,
I had forgotten my past
and was in a daze for over 10 years.
You took care of me.
But I'm not from Orange Lake.
I have a past you don't know about
and a future you don't understand.
I am not Pei Jiu.
This notebook and you
have nothing to do with me.
Do you understand?
I understand.
That's good.
I'm about to leave this place.
Take care of yourself.
You too,
Mr. Lu Chen.
Pei Jiu won't come back anymore,
will he?
No, he won't.
I'll go out and have a look.
Do you really not remember anything?
Though the dream was beautiful,
it was nothing more than an illusion.
Now that I've awakened, my original intention remains unchanged.
There are more important things
waiting for me to do.
Lu Chen is still Lu Chen.
Is Yuanzhong still Yuanzhong?
Of course.
That's good.
[Orange Lake]
Immortal elders,
the villagers of Orange Lake have gathered
to wish you a safe journey.
Have a safe journey.
Why must Lu Chen
come with us?
Although he's a weapon spirit,
he has long since developed consciousness
and become an independent individual.
Can't we let him
choose based on his own preferences?
This is the path he has chosen.
You're only considering it
from Pei Jiu's perspective.
Why not consider Lu Chen's perspective?
Because
at least Pei Jiu
was much happier than Lu Chen.
[Yesterday's Inn] [Closed]
♫I lament the countless ups and downs♫
♫The wind of fate disrupts my life♫
♫What's real? What's fake?♫
♫Good and evil blur together as I race through the mortal world♫
Why do you think the landlady
is setting off fireworks in broad daylight?
♫Racing forward, scars all along the way♫
She can set off fireworks if she wants to.
♫Yet my gaze stays firm and unwavering♫
Look,
isn't it beautiful?
♫Cutting through this cold, bitter world♫
♫I may be as insignificant as dust♫
♫But I still dare to fight the stars♫
♫With my unyielding soul♫
♫When the world collapses♫
♫I'll draw my sword for you, without a second thought♫
♫Fate is unpredictable like a flickering flame♫
♫I wield love and hate like a blade♫
♫I race fearlessly♫
♫Fate is unpredictable like a flickering flame♫
♫I wield love and hate like a blade♫
♫Fearlessly roaming across the world♫
[Pei Jiu loves Yunniang]
Who will win in the end?
Come on,
let's do it again.
Come on, come on.
I'm four.
No, no, no.
I didn't call it out.
Zi Fei, hurry up and try again.
You—
Come on, come on.
I-I didn't call it out again.
Hey, how can you cheat like that?
When will they finish?
Zi Fei has terrible luck in gambling.
It'll be a while before he wins.
So where are we
going next?
For the remaining two seals,
one is in Yandu
and the other is in the middle of Su River.
I've heard that Yandu is the city of craftsmanship
and is very prosperous.
The markets there are filled with precious goods,
houses are full of fine silks, and carriages stream like water.
Even at night,
there's music and dancing,
and the lights never go out.
Zi Fei is so eager to win.
Could it be because if he wins,
he can go to Yandu?
No, he wants to go to Su River.
Su River?
That place is remote.
It's far away and sparsely populated.
Why would he want to go there?
You lost this time, didn't you?
It doesn't count. You were too slow.
Let's do it again, come on.
It doesn't count again?
You're just a sore loser.
Yes,
I just want to go to Su River
to bring Ling Yao out.
You and Lu Chen can accompany them to Yandu,
and that's that!
What do you mean?
No way.
I want to go to Su River to pick up Ling Yao too.
With your dull appearance,
do you think she would like you?
What are you going there for?
Nonsense!
Ling Yao likes me very much.
Ling Yao is a woman?
A beautiful woman.